# 哈喽 大家好
Hello everyone
# 前段时间有很多粉丝在问
Previously there are many fans asking
# 这个鱼片切出来会不会里面有刺
If there are many fishbones in fish slices
# 会不会吃了卡喉咙
would its bones get stuck in throat
# 今天我就杀条鱼
# I’m going to slice this fish
# 给你们解决这个疑惑
to address your concerns
# 先放血
Let’s bleed this fish
# 好 放好血之后我们来打鳞
# Okay, after fish bleeds out, clean its scales
# 其实我们正常来说
Honestly to me
# 按照以前我的速度杀一条鱼的话
Gutter a fish at my regular pace
# 也就两三分钟吧
In just 2 or 3 minutes
# 两三分钟是把它杀好洗干净
# Gutter and clean fish in 2 to 3 minutes
# 去鱼鳞去鱼肚
# Including clean fish scales and its maw
# 然后再把它剁出来
# and cut it to slices
# 如果不起片的情况下
If my kitchen knife holds well
# 好 我拿去洗一下
# Oaky I am going to wash it
# 然后把这个鱼擦一下
And dry the fish
# 首先从这里切一刀跟鲤鱼是一样的
Fist of all, slice here, same as how I cut carp
# 然后往上面走
# Then cut all the away up
# 你们新手一定要拿个毛巾来
Amateurs must need a towel to grasp
# 因为这个鱼比较滑
# Because the fish is slippery
# 然后翻过来
# Then flip it over
# 这个就晚上拿给你做水煮鱼吃
# I am going to cook “shui zhu fish” for you tonight
# 可以安
# Great
# 好 这个鱼片就解出来了
# Okay, now we have cut the fish
# 我们片鱼的时候
# When we slice the fish
# 这样子压着
# Press it down like this
# 同样也是（讲过的）这个就不教了
Same as I showed before, not going to teach again
# 上次都看过了
# We have learned before
# 好 鱼皮我们就片出来了
# Okay, we have sliced the fish
# 现在我们的鱼片
# Now our fish slices
# 片成这种一片一片的了
# are cut into pieces like this
# 这么厚
# Very think
# 这中间有没有鱼刺
# So is there fishbone in the slices
# 我跟大家说这里面是有鱼刺的
# I want to let you know there is
# 但是它这个鱼刺不长
# But the fishbone is tiny
# 来 我们把它煮熟一片
Okay, let‘s cook some slices
# 然后把它碾碎了
And ground them
# 看一下里面的鱼刺到底有多长
# To check what size the fishbones are
# 看 都熟了
# Look, it is all boiled
# 肯定撒 没得好大一片嘛
# Of course, it is a large piece
# 好了 我们这个鱼片已经焯好水出来了
Oaky, we have fish slices scalded
# 就是已经熟了
# It is well cooked
# 现在我们把这个鱼片把它弄开
# Now we are going to ground the fish
# 我们来看一下里面到底有没有刺
# Let’s see if there are fishbones
# ok 找到一根刺了
# okay, find one
# 有是有 很短
# There are some, but short
# 这根
# This one
# 所以的话
# In conclusion
# 我们通过这次实验找出来的刺当中
# We have found fishbones in this experiment
# 斜刀的有比较长的
Slant-cut leaves long fish bones
# 我建议你们普通家庭里面切这个鱼片
# I would recommend when you slice fish at home
# 直刀往下面切 切薄一点
# Cut even more straight and thinner
# 它的鱼刺就鱼片多厚
The thickness of fish slice
# 鱼刺就有多长
Determines the size of fishbones
# 因为它的刺的话它是斜着长的
# Because its bones are naturally at an angle
# 你又正好斜着片
# And if you are slant cutting
# 它里面肯定有稍微长一点的刺
It will leave longer fishbone
# 如果是竖着切的话
# If you would cut straight
# 它的刺就相当于是这样横着切断了
The fishbone will be cut off horizontally
# 如果你们想吃
If you are craving
# 确实是想吃
Really craving for fish
# 没有多少刺的话
With less fishbone
# 可以换鱼换成鲈鱼啊
You can choose bass fish over carp
# 比如一些海鱼
# Such as deep-sea fishes
# 它的刺就非常少
# There is way less fish bones
# 下面开始今天真正的表演“松鼠鱼”
# Next is today’s real cooking show for “squirrel fish”
# 哈喽 大家好
Hello everyone
# 今天我用这条草鱼做一个松鼠鱼
I am going to cook the dish with a grass carp
# 给我四伯吃
For my uncle
# 我们先来说下这个草鱼放血怎么放
# Let’s see how to bleed the grass carp
# 一般就是用一只手抓住它
Usually just grasp it with one hand
# 然后用这个尖刀
Then use a short knife
# 把这个他它前面这个鱼鳞刮掉
# Scrape off the scales here
# 然后就在这个位置
Then at this point
# 这个位置
# Right here
# 这是它的心脏
Here is its heart
# Here is its heart
# 一下子就流出来了
# It bleeds out right away
# 这条鱼小它没有什么血
It’s a small fish with not much blood
# 所有的鱼当中这个草鱼的鳞是最好打的
Out of all fishes, it is easiest to scrape grass carp
# 吃鱼就要吃这种 小个点的
Ideal fish to eat, small one
# 斤多点的这种
Couple pounds (fish)
# 草鱼就要吃两斤多三斤以下的
Grass fish around 2 or 3 pounds is best